MICHAEL J. HARRIS

681 W 920 N OREM, UT 84057

CELL PHONE #: (801) 850-7115 **EMAIL:** MICHAELJH7@GMAIL.COM

BRIEF INTRODUCTION

As an industrious self-starting professional and possessing excellent skills in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML and CSS, I am dedicated to the success of both your business and the customers that I'll be serving. With integrity at work and home, I am resolved to live by the principles of respect, honesty, cooperation, leadership, and vision. I utilize these principles through the skills I possess of effective software development, empowering communication, and outstanding technical expertise. I look forward to serving your organization with the highest commitment and talent I have to offer in contributing to the success of your business and customer satisfaction!

EXPERIENCE

BUSINESS OWNER: SOFTWARE DEVELOPER / WEBSITE DESIGNER / GRAPHIC ARTIST / MUSICIAN

Orem, Utah

Pyramex Games, LLC

January 2010 - Present

- Developing fun RPG, adventure, and educational games for mobile devices, Windows, and Mac
- Software development work includes JavaScript programming, graphic art design, music compilation, sound editing, app testing, app submission, web design, and marketing

SALES REPRESENTATIVE Orem, Utah

Slingshot, Inc

March 2017 - May 2017

- Successfully selling pest control accounts for over 50 pest control offices via phone
- Efficiently identifying coding bugs and software improvement ideas that allow for software's continuous improvement

TRAVEL SALES REPRESENTATIVE: SALES AGENT / SOFTWARE TESTER

Lehi, Utah

Partner Fusion, inc.

March 2015 - December 2016

- Delivered exceptional customer satisfaction in selling hotel reservations that met the quality and price customers needed
- Successfully identified coding bugs and software improvement ideas that allowed for the software's continuous improvement

WEB ADVISOR: TECHNICAL SUPPORT / SALES AGENT

Orem, Utah

Bluehost Inc.

April 2013 - March 2015

- Resolved technical concerns with hosting DNS, website security, and website creation in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and PHP
- Successfully sold premium hosting packages, SEO suites, partner products, upgraded services, and more

BUSINESS OWNER: IOS APP DEVELOPER / IOS APP PUBLISHER / PROGRAMMER / GRAPHIC ARTIST CreAtiV Games, LLC

August 2010 - January 2015

- Developed and published fun educational apps for the iOS devices of iPhone, iPod Touch, and iPad.
- Software development work included programming, graphic art design, voice narration, music compilation, sound editing, app testing, app submission, web design, and marketing

AUTO/HOME/COMMERCIAL INSURANCE BROKER

Orem, Utah

Advance Insurance

October 2009 - August 2010

- Licensed with the state of Utah to sell Property and Casualty insurance in Utah
- Solicit auto, home, and commercial insurance coverage for low premiums through the 40+ insurance agencies I represented

EDUCATION

WEB DEVELOPER CERTIFICATE (In process - Currently Enrolled)

Bottega School of Technology

Lehi, Utah

Present

HTML, CSS AND JAVASCRIPT CERTIFICATIONS

W3Schools Certification

w3schools.com December 2016

PROPERTY AND CASUALTY INSURANCE LICENSE

Salt Lake City, Utah October 2009

State of Utah Department of Insurance

SOPHOMORE — BEHAVIORAL SCIENCE MAJOR

Orem, Utah

Utah Valley University

2002-2003

SKILLS

- Exceptional coding skills in Ruby, Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- knowledge in Typescript, Angular, React, JQuery, PHP, C, C++, and Assembly programming languages
- Outstanding graphic creation skills in Photoshop, Fuse, 3d Studio Max Release 7.0, 6.0, 4.2, and PaintShop Photo Pro
- Excellent document creation skills in Microsoft Office Word, Excel, Google Drive products and 73 WPM in typing
- Fantastic communication, sales, customer service, internet and computer technology skills Fluently speak the Cebuano, Ilonggo, Capiznon, and Aklanon dialects of the Philippines

VOLUNTEER

- 1999-2001 served a full-time mission for two years for The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-Day Saints in the Philippines
- 1999-2002 taught English to 20+ people in the Philippines and the ESL department of UVU
- 2001-2003 helped in the training of 50+ missionaries in the LDS Missionary Training Center to speak Cebuano